gain control of Target creature either
you're a blue Mage and you love it or
you're on the receiving end and you hate
it
taking control of other players
creatures permanently is usually
reserved for those playing blue but in
today's video I'm going to show you how
you can change Act of treason from being
a temporary control effect into a
permanent one and all you need to do is
add a little splash of white to your
decks and have a basic understanding of
what happens when things change zones
and game objects to start an object is
effectively anything in the game
an ability on the stack a card a copy of
a card a token a spell a permanent or an
emblem okay got that nice and easy
Next Step let's go into a really basic
game situation
let's say I have a land or else in play
and my opponent attempts to shock it in
response I cast momentary blink the
spell resolves Lana or elf gets exiled
and then comes back under my control
but does it still die to shock
in this case no and that's thanks to
this rule here an object that moves from
one zone to another becomes a new game
object with no memory or relation to its
previous existence now there are eight
exceptions to this rule but they're not
really relevant here so we're not going
to cover them today let's go back to the
example Atlanta Royals is being targeted
by shock in response we momentary blink
it dispel resolves our Lana moralf goes
to Exile but when it comes back they are
a new game object and even though it's
the same card shock has now completely
lost its original Target who I have
never met this man in my life and
because of that the spell Fizzles and
Lana War elves lives to see another day
so we now know that when an object
changes zones it's treated as a new game
object
so how can we abuse this and steal
creatures permanently in Boris colors
let's go over how we normally steal
creatures in red
most red take control of creatures
effects all have very similar wording to
act of treason some of them even come
with an additional effect
in this case Act of treason is a three
Mana sorcery that says gain control of
Target creature until end of turn untap
that creature it gains haste until end
of turn
so effectively when we Act of treason
our opponent's creature we gain control
of it and it comes with a little note
also known as a delayed trigger that
says at the end of turn return me to my
owner
now it would be an awful shame if that
creature was to somehow lose that little
reminder
with a little bit of digging there are a
number of cards that can help us refresh
a creature and cause them to forget that
delayed trigger allowing us to keep that
creature permanently
let's check out Cloud shift Cloud shift
is a one Mana instant that says Exile
Target creature you control then return
that card to the battlefield under your
control
on the surface this card looks exactly
like momentary blink but if we take a
closer look there's a key difference in
the wording that makes this whole trick
work
momentary blink Returns the blinked
creature to its owner's control whereas
Cloud shift specifically says to return
that creature to the battlefield under
our control so now let's combine
everything we've learned to start
permanently stealing creatures in our
Boris control deck
we cast active treason on our opponent's
creature we might be able to get an
attack in or use its activated ability
if it has one
and once we're ready we cast Cloud shift
targeting it
the creature gets exiled becomes a new
game object and forgets everything
that's just happened to it
it comes back to the battlefield under
our control nice and clean with no
delayed triggered abilities attached to
it which means we've now permanently
gained control over a creature in our
white and red deck
so there you have it how to steal
creatures in your Boris colored deck if
you learned something in this video be
sure to give it a like if you've got any
other rules questions or cool
interactions that you know let me know
down in the comments below otherwise
check out this video YouTube thinks
you'll like thanks for watching and I'll
see you in the next one